（九尾）いけ　ナルト！
Go... Naruto.
てめえは失敗なんかしねえ！
You won't fail!
（ナルト）オッス！
（ガイ）おっ？
Yeah!
《また　あの力か》
That power again, huh?
カカシ　俺たちも…　んっ？
Kakashi, we ought to—!
（カカシ）やつは…　まさか…。
That man, he couldn't be...
いや…。
（ガイ）カカシ。
No...
そんなバカなことが…。
– Kakashi...
– There's absolutely no way!
（ガイ）カカシ！　聞いているのか？
Kakashi!
Are you listening?
やつを攻めるには
陽動の手数がキモになる。
The more diversions,
the better when attacking him!
俺たちも戦うぞ！
We have to join the fight!
（ガイ）お前が今
何を考えているのかは→
I've got a pretty good idea
of what you're thinking right now.
想像がつく。　俺もそうだ。
I feel the same way...
だが　そいつは置いとけ。
今は感傷に浸る暇はない。
But leave it be.
There's no time to wallow
in sentimentality.
部下だったナルトが
お前より先に突っ込んでんだぞ！
Your former subordinate, Naruto,
has already jumped into action!
バカが…。
１人で突っ込んでくるとはな！
How stupid, jumping in alone!
（ビー）ヨウヨウ！　しまった！
Yo! Yo!
Damn it!
俺１人で
突っ込んでんじゃねえよ。
I'm not alone!
九喇嘛を忘れんな。
Don't forget Kurama!
それに
ビーのおっちゃんに　八っつぁん。
There's also Octopops and Eight-o...
ゲキマユ先生に　カカシ先生もいる！
Bushier Brow Sensei!
And Kakashi Sensei too!
俺との勝負で
勝ち越しているお前が→
You've got a winning record
against me right now...
この程度で
老いぼれちゃいないはずだよな。
This better not be enough
to slow you down... Kakashi!
カカシ！
《カカシ：ナルト。
お前が俺の部下でよかったよ》
Naruto...
I'm glad you were
my subordinate!
いくぞ　ガイ！
Let's go... Guy!
我がライバル！　そうこなくては！
My dear rival!
That's what I'm talking about!
《残りのチャクラを考えても
できて　あと数発》
Considering my remaining chakra...
I only have a few shots left.
連発できない借り物の力など
恐るるに足らん。
I do not fear a borrowed power
that can't even string together
a barrage.
本当の神威の力。
The true power of Kamui...
《この神威　絶対にタイミングは…。
This Kamui...
I will not miss...
外せない！》
思い知れ！
– Now watch and learn!
– my timing!
んっ。
《術のタネがわかったところで
変わらん》
Their knowing the trick to
my jutsu changes nothing.
（ビー）入れるときに実体化するなら
出すときも実体化するはずだ！
If he has to materialize
when he takes things in,
he has to do so when
he spits things out too!
今がチャンスだぜ！
This is our chance!
反撃できればの話だが。
That's if you can counterstrike!
《うっ…　これは！？》
What is this?
ナルト！　こいつは
尾獣の力を拘束する→
Naruto!
These have Curse Marks on them
that restrain Tailed Beast power.
呪印付きだ！　いいか！
絶対に触るんじゃねえぞ！
Whatever you do, don't touch it!
ビーのおっちゃん！
Octopops!
ちょっとの間　かくまってくれ！
Could you shield me for a bit?
《影分身の術！》
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
わかった　来い！
俺が傘になる！
All right, come here!
I'll be your umbrella!
《神威！》
Kamui!
《また同じ手なら→
If it's that same trick again,
ナルトをすり抜けさせなければ
いいだけだ》
all I need to do is not have
Naruto slip through me.
なんだ　影分身か。
What? A Shadow Clone?
カカシ！
Kakashi!
うっ…。
杭のほうが速かったな。
Seems my attack was
quicker than you, Kakashi.
カカシ。　これで螺旋丸も
飛ばしそこねた。
You missed transporting away
the Rasengan...
また神威の無駄遣いだな。
... and wasted another Kamui.
《まだだ！　尾獣玉！》
Not yet!
Tailed Beast Bomb!
《少し遅い。　無駄なことを》
A bit late. How futile.
（ガイ）くっ。
おっ　お前は…。
You're—!
うずまきナルトだ！！
Naruto Uzumaki!
《そ…　そうか。
さっきの神威は螺旋丸ではなく→
I see, so that Kamui just now
wasn't transporting the Rasengan,
影分身　そのものを飛ばしたのか。
but the Shadow Clone itself!
カカシめ…　杭よりも速く！》
He beat me to it...
Damn you, Kakashi!
てめえは…！
しまった！
Who...
Damn it!
誰だ～！
... are you?!
for some reason the moon is one size larger tonight
konya no tsuki wa nazeka hitomawari ookikute
it's shining brighter than it usually does
itsumo yori akaruku terasu
I trudge along the road home with my shoulders hunched
senaka wo marumete tobotobo kaeru michi
at any time I will always have a friend
donna toki mo mikata wa iru
without saying a word, it's all right to cry
nani mo iwazu naketara ii ne
once my tears dry, it will all be over
namida ga karetara owari
I need to become stronger...
motto boku ga tsuyoku naranakya
sorrow is the first step towards independence
kanashimi wa jiritsu he no ippo
how many times do I have to get hurt to forget the pain?
nando kizutsukeba itami wo wasureru
when I bleed red, I'm reminded of life
akai chi wo nagaseba inochi wo omoidasu sa
I collapse on the road with my arms and legs spread out
michi ni taore dainoji ni
I look up at the sky and think
sora wo miagete omou
true loneliness is someone without a past
shin no kodoku to wa kako no nai mono
someone who only knows the present
ima shika shiranu mono
Who Are You?
NINJA ACADEMY ORIENTATION
CHUNIN EXAM STAGE TWO
SQUAD VS. SQUAD BATTLES
KAKASHI         GUY          IBIKI
OBITO            EBISU        HAYATE
RIN               GENMA        TOKARA
CHUNIN EXAM STAGE 3
INDIVIDUAL BATTLES
CHUNIN
[TOP OF CERTIFICATE]
PLAN BY KAKASHI'S CLASSMATES
TO OBTAIN GIFTS TO CELEBRATE
HIS PROMOTION TO JONIN.
(TOP SECRET MISSION)
PLAN BY KAKASHI'S CLASSMATES
TO OBTAIN GIFTS TO CELEBRATE
HIS PROMOTION TO JONIN.
(TOP SECRET MISSION)
As of today, Kakashi is
a jonin just like me.
（ミナト）今日から　カカシは　俺と同じ
上忍に就任したんだよね。
（リン）この前
ちゃんと話したでしょ　オビト。
Remember, we were talking
about this just the other day, Obito?
When we discussed
getting Kakashi a gift!
カカシに　プレゼントあげようって。
Sorry. I guess I wasn't listening.
（オビト）悪い　聞いてなかった。
Well, I got you this.
A custom-made kunai.
（ミナト）俺は　これをあげるね。
特注クナイだよ。
It's a little heavy and unconventional.
少し重くていびつだけど
慣れると使いやすいよ。
But you'll get used to it quickly.
（カカシ）どうも。
Thank you.
I got you this!
私は　これ！　はい！
Here! A personalized med kit for you.
個人用特別医療パック。
I just adjusted a few things
to make it easier to use.
すべて使いやすいように
改良してあるからさ。
サンキュー。
Thank you.
What are you holding
your hand out for?
ん…。
（オビト）な…　なんだよ　その手は！
Kakashi's father,
Sakumo, took his own life
カカシの父　サクモさんは→
after everyone around him
vilified him.
中傷されて　ご自分で
自分の命を絶たれたんだ。
This is where we go our separate ways.
（ミナト）ここからは　二手に分かれる。
Let's get going...
さっさと行こうぜ　隊長さんよ。
Captain.
Fire Style: Fire Ball Jutsu!
《火遁　豪火球の術！》
We'll be taking this one with us.
こいつは　預からせてもらう。
Do you have any idea
what you're saying, Kakashi?!
お前　今なに言ってんのか
自分でわかってんのか！？
Yeah...
ああ。
２人で
このまま任務を続行する。
The two of us have to complete
the mission alone.
And Rin? What do we do
about Rin, huh?
リンは　リンはどうすんだよ！
We'll come back for her later.
リンは　後回しだ。
We must carry out our mission
even at the expense of our comrades.
仲間を犠牲にしてでも
任務の遂行が絶対だ。
You're right. In the Ninja World,
確かに　忍の世界で→
those who break the rules and
laws are regarded as scum.
ルールや　掟を破るやつは
クズ呼ばわりされる。
But...
けどな…。
those who would abandon
even one of their friends,
仲間を大切にしないやつは
それ以上のクズだ！
are far worse than scum.
Found them!
見つけたぞ！
Kakashi? Why did you—?
（オビト）カカシ…　お前どうして。
Well, I certainly can't leave this up
to a crybaby ninja like you, can I?
ま！　お前みたいな
泣き虫忍者に→
１人で任せておけないでしょ。
Kakashi...
カカシ…。
Obito, behind you!
オビト　後ろだ！
ぐあっ！　目が…。
My eye...!
Kakashi!
カカシ！
Hey, Kakashi! Are you all right?!
おいカカシ　大丈夫か！
B-But how?
な　なぜだ。
見えるわけはない。
There's no way that
you could've seen me!
Obito... How did you...?!
オビト　お前…。
Release!
解！
Kakashi... Obito...
カカシ　オビト…。
This is bad!
やばい！
Whatever the village
or anyone else may say...
里のやつらが
なんて言おうと→
I think that you're a great jonin...
お前は　立派な上忍だ。
It's true, that's how I feel.
それが　俺の気持だ。
Please accept this...
(受け取ってくれ))
Is that you... Obito?
（カカシ）お前は…　オビト？
Are you really Obito?
（ガイ）本当に　オビトなのか？
I thought you died!
死んだはずだろ…。
間違いない…。
There's no mistake.
That's Obito Uchiha...
うちはオビトだ。
You can call me by
that name if you want.
（オビト）その名で呼びたいのであれば
好きに呼べばいい。
It means nothing to me.
俺には　なんの意味もない。
((ぐあっ　目が！
カカシ！
My eye!
Kakashi!
Obito... How did you...?!
オビト　お前…。
This time,
I will protect my comrade!
(ここは…　仲間は俺が守る！))
But that day, you...
お前は…　あのとき…。
Run for the exit!
((みんな　出口へ走れ！
Kakashi!
うっ…。
（オビト）カカシ！
You guys all right? Rin? Kakashi?
（オビト）大丈夫か…。
リン…　カカシ…。
Obito!
（カカシ）オビト！
うっ…　うぐっ…。
No, don't. It's okay, Kakashi.
やめろ…　いいんだ　カカシ。
I don't think... I'll make it.
俺は…　もう　ダメみたいだ。
My right side is completely crushed.
体の右側は
ほとんど潰れちまって…。
I can't even feel anything
there anymore.
感覚すら…　ねえ。
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。
So what if I'm captain now?!
何が隊長だ！　何が上忍だ！
So what if I made jonin?!
そういや…　忘れてたぜ。
Oh, that's right, I totally forgot...
I was the only one...
俺だけ　お前に→
who didn't give you
a gift for making jonin, Kakashi.
上忍祝いのプレゼント…
やってなかったな　カカシ…。
I'm giving you my Sharingan.
この…
俺の写輪眼をやるからよ…。
Kakashi, take care of Rin...
カカシ…。
リンを頼むぜ…。
I will.
ああ…。
Obito!
(オビト～！))
Obito...
《カカシ：オビト…》
You're alive...
（カカシ）生きて…　いたのか…。
Who is he?
誰だってばよ！？
He was our classmate and
an Uchiha who was a Leaf Shinobi.
（ガイ）俺たちの同期で
木ノ葉の忍だった　うちはの男だ。
We all thought he was killed
in action during the last war.
前の戦争で
戦死したはずだったが…。
If you survived, why didn't you
come forward sooner?
生きていたなら…
なぜ　今まで…。
It's irrelevant whether
I had survived or not.
俺が生きていたか
どうかなんてのは→
どうでもいいことだ…。
Although, I suppose...
しかし…　そうだな。
If you really want an answer...
なぜかと　あえて問うなら…。
It's because...
お前が　リンを…。
you let Rin...
見殺しにしたから…。
die.
だろうな。
フッ…　早まるな。　それに…。
Relax...
Besides, what's with
that look, Kakashi?
そんな顔するな　カカシ。
You're not going to condemn me?
俺を責めないのか？
What would I gain from criticizing
this absurd reality at this point?
こんな　くだらない現実を
今さら責めて　何になる。
I have no interest in the affairs
これから消える世界のことなどに
興味はない。
of a world that shall
soon cease to exist.
Kakashi Sensei!
カカシ先生！
I don't know what went down
between you two,
こいつとの間に
何があったのかは知らねえが→
but this is no time to be depressed!
こんなとこで
落ち込んでる場合じゃねえだろ！
We can discuss it later!
話はあとで　じっくり聞く！
Right now, stopping what this guy
is trying to do comes first!
今は　こいつの
やろうとしていることを→
止めるのが先だってばよ！
Naruto!
《ナルト…》
Kakashi! Naruto is absolutely right!
カカシ！　ナルトの言うとおりだ！
The fate of this world currently
rests in our hands!
今は　世界が
俺たちの手にかかってるんだ！
I have nothing more
to talk to you about.
お前らに話すことは　何もない。
Stay tied down to reality...
現実に縛られたまま…
火遁…。
Fire Style...
and die!
死ね。
Bomb Blast Dance!
爆風乱舞！
The Nine Tails' tail, huh?
九尾の尾か。
Huh? What the—?!
何だ！？
Looks like you're having fun
over here...
（マダラ）こっちは楽しそうだな…。
Obito.
（マダラ）オビト…。
gozen reiji akari kieta machi
At midnight, in a city where the lights are out
koyoi wa odore tipsy night
I'm going to dance tonight Tipsy Night
tsukiakari mo todokanu basho ni wa
In a place where the moonlight doesn't reach
kodoku sae mo utau machi ga aru
There's a city that brings loneliness
kuruisou na furuesou na itami dake ga
There's only a maddening pain that makes me tremble
kowaresou na nakushisou na houseki da
It's like a fragile gemstone that could be easily lost
kuraberareru koto nado ubawareru koto nado nai
There's nothing to compare it to and it can't be stolen
kimi wa kimi de ii, saa waratte misete
You should just be yourself, Now show me a smile
nani mo kangaezutomo soko ni riyuu ga nakutomo
Even you don't think, Even if there is no reason
sore koso ga subarashii hajimari
This is a wonderful beginning
saa, yoake da
Now, dawn is about to break
gozen reiji akari kieta machi
At midnight, in a city where the lights are out
furikaereba sasou black night town
I look back and it beckons me Black Night Town
He's... Madara!
＜旬の野菜が大好きな豆助＞
Madara? You mean that Madara?
♪～
Why? Why is that Madara
over here?
Hey, Naruto!
Him being here must mean...
≫豆助
What's happened to
everyone over there?!
きょうのお野菜は
今が旬のアレよ？
I'm not sure, but I suspect...
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"Obito and Madara"
＜　その野菜とは…＞
... that none of them
are doing too well.